设计抽象数据类型涉及
Designing an abstract data type involves
选择好的操作并确定
choosing good operations and determining
他们应该怎么做。
how they should behave.
这里有一些经验法则。
Here a few rules of thumb.
首先，最好有几个简单的操作
First, it's better to have a few simple operations that
可以用强有力的方式组合而不是
can be combined in powerful ways rather than
很多复杂的操作。
lots of complex operations.
每个操作都应该有明确的目的
Each operation should have a well-defined purpose
应该有连贯的行为而不是
and should have a coherent behavior rather than
很多特殊情况。
a lot of special cases.
所以我们可能不应该添加sum操作
So we probably shouldn't add a sum operation
举个例子。
to List, for example.
它可能有助于处理整数列表的客户机，
It might help with clients who work with lists of integers,
但是列表是用来做其他事情的
but List is used for other things
还有，比如字符串列表，或者列表列表。
as well, like lists of strings, or lists of lists.
所有这些特殊情况都会使sum成为一个困难的操作
All these special cases would make sum a hard operation
理解和使用。
to understand and use.
现在这套操作在意义上应该是足够的
Now the set of operations should be adequate in the sense
必须有足够的资源来做这些事
that there must be enough to do the kinds
客户端可能要做的计算。
of computations clients are likely to want to do.
良好的测试检查每个属性
Good tests check that every property
这种类型的对象可以用一些观察者来提取。
of an object of the type can be extracted with some observer.
例如，如果没有get操作，
For example, if there were no get operation,
我们无法找出列表中的元素
we wouldn't be able to find out what the elements of a list
是。
are.
所以基本信息不应该过分
So basic information should not be inordinately
很难获得。
difficult to obtain.
例如，size方法并不严格
For example, the size method is not strictly
必须列出，因为我们能做的
necessary for List, because what we could do
是应用不断增加的指数，直到我们得到一个失败。
is apply get on increasing indices until we get a failure.
但这是低效和不方便的。
But this is inefficient and inconvenient.
这是不够的。
It's not adequate.
现在您创建的类型可能是泛型，
Now the type you're creating might be generic,
像一个列表，或一个集合，或一个图表，用于抽签
like a list, or a set, or a graph, used for lots
在不同的情况下。
of different situations.
或者它可能是特定领域的，比如街道
Or it might be domain-specific, like a street
地图，员工数据库，电话簿。
map, or an employee database, or a phone book.
但不应该混合使用一般特性和特定于域的特性。
But you should not mix generic and domain-specific features.
如果要创建甲板类型
If you create a Deck type intended
为了表示一系列扑克牌，
to represent a sequence of playing cards,
你可能不应该有一个通用的add方法
you probably shouldn't have a generic add method
接受任意对象，
that accepts an arbitrary object,
例如整数或字符串。
like an integer or a string.
你应该坚持打牌。
You should stick to cards.
相反，这是没有意义的
Conversely, it wouldn't make sense
把特定于域的方法，比如dealCards，
to put a domain-specific method, like dealCards,
进入泛型类型列表。
into a generic type List.
现在关键的是，一个好的抽象数据类型
Now critically, a good abstract data type
应独立于代表。
should be representation independent.
这意味着使用抽象数据类型
This means that the use of an abstract data type
独立于它的表示，实际数据
is independent of its representation, the actual data
用于实现它的结构或数据字段，
structure or data fields that are used to implement it,
所以这个表示的变化
so that changes in that representation
对抽象类型本身之外的代码没有影响
have no effect on code outside the abstract type itself
对它的客户。
on its clients.
例如，List提供的操作
For example, the operations offered by List
与列表是否表示为链接无关
are independent of whether the list is represented as a linked
列表或作为数组。
list or as an array.
您将无法更改ADT的表示形式
You won't be able to change the representation of an ADT
除非它的运作完全
at all unless its operations are fully
用前置条件和后置条件指定
specified with preconditions and postconditions
让客户知道该依赖什么，
so that clients know what to depend on,
你知道你可以安全地改变什么。
and you know what you can safely change.
你需要这些方法的所有规格。
You need all of those specs on those methods.
让我们看一个例子。
Let's look at an example.
让我们看一个简单的抽象数据类型
Let's look at a simple abstract data type
看看代表独立意味着什么
to see what representation independence means
为什么有用。
and why it's useful.
我们要看一根绳子。
We're going to look at a string.
这将类似于
This will be similar to the string type that's
内置到Java中，但它的操作要少得多。
built into Java, but it's going to have far fewer operations.
规格会有点不同。
And the specs will be a little different.
所以我们称之为我的字符串。
So we'll call it mystring.
这是ADT的规格。
Now here are the specs for that ADT.
首先，有个标题说，
First of all, there's a header that says,
这应该代表一个不可变的序列
well this is supposed to represent an immutable sequence
角色的。
of characters.
这就是绳子。
That's what a string is.
重要的是，我们在这里说它是不可变的。
It's important that we say here that it's immutable.
在以后的阅读中我们会经常讨论这个问题。
We'll talk about that a lot in future reading.
我们有每种手术的例子
And we have an example of each kind of operation
这里，或者至少所有
here, or at least all the ones that make
对不可变类型的检测。
sense on an immutable type.
我们这里没有突变子。
We don't have a mutator here.
我们有一个创造者。
We've got a creator.
我们的创造者将会非常简单。
And our creator is going to be very simple.
它实际上只是取一个布尔值
It's actually just going to take a Boolean value
给你一个布尔值的字符串表示
and give you a string representation of that Boolean
值，为真或为假。
value, either true or false.
所以这将是一个非常有限的数据类型
So this is really going to be a very limited data type
马上。
right now.
但这是个很好的例子。
But it's good as an example.
这里有几个观察者操作。
And here's a couple of observer operations.
长度给出了字符串中的字符数。
Length gives us the number of characters in the string.
CharAt给了我们位置I的角色，
CharAt gives us the character at position I,
它有一个先决条件。
and it has a precondition on that I.
然后我们有一个生产商运作的例子。
And then we have an example of a producer operation.
子字符串给我们一个字符串
Substring gives us a string consisting
从位置开始的字符数
of the characters from position start
在调用此项的字符串中定位结束。
to position end in the string that you are calling this on.
这是一个实例方法。
This is an instance method.
它有一个开始和结束的先决条件。
And it has a precondition on start and end.
现在这些公共操作和它们的规格
Now these public operations and their specs
是此数据类型的客户端的唯一信息
are the only information that a client of this data type
允许知道，在第一次测试编程之后
is allowed to know, following the test first programming
范式。
paradigm.
实际上，我们应该创建的第一个客户机
In fact, the first client we should create
是一个测试套件，它根据
is a test suite that exercises these operations according
他们的规格。
to their specs.
但目前，在使用assert equals的测试用例中，
But at the moment, in test cases that use assert equals,
J units断言equals，直接在mystring对象上是行不通的。
J units assert equals, directly on mystring objects won't work.
我们没有在mystring上定义相等操作。
We don't have an equality operation defined on mystring.
我们将仔细讨论如何实现平等
We'll talk about how to implement equality carefully
稍后再阅读。
later in a later reading.
但目前我们只能用mystring执行的操作
But for now the only operations we can perform with mystring
是我们上面定义的那些。
are the ones we've defined above.
长度、字符和子字符串的值。
Value of length, charAt, and substring.
所以我们的测试必须局限于这些操作。
So our tests have to limit themselves to those operations.
这其实不是一个可怕的限制。
That's actually not a terrible limitation.
例如，这里有一个值为operation的测试。
For example, here's one test with a value of operation.
我们会让它成真的。
We're going to give it true.
我们要拿回一根绳子。
We're going to get a string back.
然后我们要在弦上运行一些观察程序
And then we're going to run some observers on the string
我们回来确认结果是
that we got back to confirm that it produced the result that we
希望如此。
expect it to.
我们要一个四字的字符串，字母是t-r-u-e，
We want a string of length four whose letters are t-r-u-e,
按顺序。
in that order.
我们将回到如何
We'll come back to the question of how
更详细地测试adt
to test ADTs in a little more detail
在阅读结束时。
at the end of this reading.
但现在，让我们来看一个简单的表示
But for now, let's look at a simple representation
为了我的字符串。
for mystring.
我们进去挖吧。
Let's dig inside.
假设我们将其表示为一个字符数组。
Suppose we represent it just as an array of characters.
这个阵列正好是这条带子的长度，
And that array is exactly the length of this strip,
最后没有多余的房间。
with no extra room at the end.
下面是内部表示
Now here's how that internal representation
将声明为内部实例
will be declared as an internal instance
类中的变量。
variable within the class.
有了这样的选择，
And with that choice of representation,
操作可以实现
the operations can be implemented
以非常直接的方式。
in a very straightforward way.
所以创造者的价值应该取布尔值
So value of the creator that's supposed to take a Boolean
给你一个字符串，不管是真是假
and give you a string either true or false according
对于布尔值来说
to the value of that Boolean-- well
它需要创建一个新的mystring对象。
it needs to create a new mystring object.
它需要把里面的数组设置为
And it needs to set the array that's inside it to either
包含字母t-r-u-e的字符数组，
a character array containing the letters t-r-u-e,
或包含字母f-a-l-s-e的字符数组。
or a character array containing the letters f-a-l-s-e.
这是基于B的值。
And that switched based on the value of B.
注意我们用的是三元的，条件的，
And notice we're using the ternary, the conditional,
Java提供给我们的运算符
operator here that Java provides us to make
更紧凑一点。
that a little more compact.
然后返回字符串值。
And then we return that string value.
Length只需查看该数组并返回其长度。
Length simply looks at that array and returns it's length.
它的长度不是4就是5。
And It's length is either going to be four or five.
查拉特拿起索引并查找它。
CharAt takes the index and looks it up.
在数组中查找相应的索引。
Looks up the corresponding index in the array.
子串有点复杂。
Substring is a little bit more complicated.
它需要构造一个新的字符串来表示
It needs to construct a new string representing
子字符串。
the substring.
它需要创建适当大小的数组
It needs to create the array of the appropriate size
在新的子串中。
in that new substring.
它将是结束和开始之间距离的大小。
It's going to be the size of the distance between end and start.
然后它使用这个效用函数
And then it's using this utility function
由Java库提供
provided by the Java library that
允许我们复制数组的某一段
allows us to copy a certain segment of an array
从这个点阵到那个点阵。
from this dot array to that dot array.
现在有一个问题需要思考。
Now here is a question to ponder.
为什么不猜谜和猜谜，这两个家伙，
Why don't charAt and substring, these two guys here,
很抱歉，这两个人--
have to-- I'm sorry, these two guys here--
必须检查它们的参数是否
have to check whether their parameters are
在有效范围内。
within the valid range.
你认为会发生什么
What do you think is going to happen
如果客户端调用这些实现
if the client calls these implementations
非法输入。
with illegal inputs.
这个实现有一个问题
One problem with this implementation
是在错过表演的机会
is that it's passing up an opportunity for performance
改进。
improvement.
此数据类型是不可变的。
This data type is immutable.
所以子串操作实际上
So the substring operation doesn't actually
必须将字符复制到新数组中。
have to copy characters out into a fresh array.
它实际上可以指向最初的mystring对象
It could actually just point to the original mystring objects
字符数组并跟踪该数组中的确切位置
character array and keep track of where exactly in that array
是表示新子字符串的开始和结束
are the start and end that represent the new substring
反对。
object.
现在，一些版本的Java中的字符串实现
Now the string implementation in some versions of Java
实际上，这样做可以节省内存。
actually do this, and it does save memory.
为了实现这个优化，
So to implement this optimization,
我们可以改变这个类的内部表示
we can change the internal representation of this class
像这样的事情。
to something like this.
这是包含字符串的数组。
This is the array that contains the string somewhere inside it.
然后开始和结束表示实际的子字符串
And then start and end represent the actual substring
在那个阵营里。
of that array.
现在有了这个新的行动
Now with this new operation, the operations
现在是这样实现的。
are now implemented like this.
所以再一次，做的价值。
So again, do value of.
我们要么把它指向一个新的真数组
We are either going to point it to a new array of true
或一系列错误。
or array of false.
我们要从头到尾
And we're going to set start and end to the beginning
以及实际数组的结尾。
and end of that actual array.
Length现在不是这个数组的长度，
Length now is not the length of this array,
但它可能是数组的某个子字符串的长度。
but it might be a length of some substring of that array.
所以我们实际上返回结束减去开始。
So we actually return end minus start.
查拉特必须调整
CharAt is going to have to adjust
你要找的角色的位置
the position of the character you are asking for
根据这个起始偏移量。
according to this start offset.
子串——这是有趣的事情发生的地方。
And substring-- this is where something interesting happens.
我们正在创建这个数组的新子串，
We're creating this new substring of this array,
并称之为。
and calling it that.
该数组将指向与此数组相同的数组。
That array is going to point to the same array as this's array.
开始的位置很简单
And that start position is simply
这是开始位置的调整
going to be this's start position adjusted
按此处提供的子字符串起始位置。
by the substring start position provided here.
同样，在结束位置。
And likewise with the end position.
所以我们能做出改变
So we were able to make that change
因为mystring的现有客户端只依赖于
because mystring's existing clients depend only
在公共方法的规范上，
on the specs of its public methods,
不是在这些私人领域。
not on these private fields.
所以我们可以不用
So we can make that change without having
检查并更改所有客户端代码。
to inspect and change all that client code.
这就是代表独立的力量。
That really is the power of representation independence.